<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Marco Palma</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/boards.jpg</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIVE</title>
      <link>/project/wive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/wive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Statistical models are only focus at the estimation of the mean of a certain biomedical outcome. However, &lt;strong&gt;within-individual variability estimation&lt;/strong&gt; (WIVE) can play a role in quantifying disease risk and progression. In longitudinal studies, WIV is related to the deviation from individual mean.
Starting from mixed-effects scale-location models (MELSM), we are looking at strategies to dynamically evaluate WIV and include it into the classic statistical modelling for dynamic risk prediction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Change</title>
      <link>/project/gasc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/gasc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Words might change their meanings over time. In this project we consider a Bayesian model to study semantic change in Ancient Greek. This project comes out of an interdisciplinary effort with the collaborators listed in the publications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IM-AGE</title>
      <link>/project/im-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/im-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tensor-based morphometry (TBM) is an imaging technique that aims at showing
local differences in brain volume with respect to a common template.
TBM images are smooth but they exhibit (especially in diseased group)
higher values in some brain regions called lateral ventricles. The study of TBM images might inform about ageing effects and neurodegenerative diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vortit Italice</title>
      <link>/project/vortit-italice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/vortit-italice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We aim at studying the phenomenon of linguistic interference within written translations from Latin to Italian produced by Italian high-school students. We combine linguistic and statistical approaches in order to define the characteristics of &amp;ldquo;translationese&amp;rdquo; in the specific setting of didactic of ancient languages and we provide indications for the development of a pilot study (research in Italian).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Il presente studio si prefissa di seguire il virtuoso esempio di analisi interdisciplinari sull’interferenza linguistica nel contesto della traduzione e di applicare simili ragionamenti e metodologie al contesto della produzione scritta degli studenti e delle studentesse di scuola superiore quando traducono dal latino all&amp;rsquo;italiano. L&amp;rsquo;approccio prevede gli apporti combinati di linguistica e statistica, nello sforzo di creare un&amp;rsquo;analisi delle caratteristiche dell&amp;rsquo;italiano della traduzione (o &amp;ldquo;traduttese&amp;rdquo;) in uno specifico contesto, da porre alla base di ricerche future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Progetto ideato e sviluppato in collaborazione con Laura Bigoni.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
